Inventory of the Fred Burnett Rhodes papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Fred Burnett Rhodes papers
1944-1980
81132
Rhodes, Fred Burnett, 1913-2001
22 manuscript boxes (9.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, legal documents, staff studies, and memorabilia, relating to the American atom bomb project during World War II, political issues before the United States Senate during the 1960s, veterans' affairs, and the postal service.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1913 December 13 Born, Washington, D.C.
1936 B.A., Colgate University
1936-1941 Claims Adjustor, Maryland Casualty Company
1941 J.D., University of Maryland
1941-1947 U.S. Army Counterintelligence Unit for the Manhattan Project
1947-1949 Executive Director, Joint Congressional Committee on Atomic Energy
1949-1950 Liaison Officer, Central Intelligence Agency
1953-1955 Chief Counsel, Armed Service Committee, U.S. Senate
1955-1960 Private law practice, Washington, D.C.
1960-1964 General Counsel, Veterans Administration
1964-1969 Staff Director, Republican Policy Committee
1969-1974 Deputy Administrator, Veterans Administration
1974-1975 Chairman, Postal Rate Commission
1975 Retired from federal service
1975-1980 Executive Committee, Baptist World Alliance
2001 November 7 Died, Anderson, South Carolina
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, memoranda, legal documents, staff studies, and memorabilia, relating to the American atom bomb project during World War II, political issues before the United States Senate during the 1960s, veterans' affairs, and the postal service.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); United States. Congress. Senate.; United States. Postal Rate Commission.; United States. Veterans Administration.; Atomic bomb.; Postal service--United States.; Veterans--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.--United States.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government, 1963-1969.
Collection Contents
- U.S. Senate Republican Committee materials (Folder 1-4)
- Correspondence, 1947-1975 (Folder 5-6)
- Blackhawk Heating and Plumbing, Inc. and Donovan Construction Co. vs. The United States (Veterans Administration), 1973-1978 (Folder 7)
- Blackhawk Heating and Plumbing, Inc. and Donovan Construction Co. vs. The United States (Veterans Administration), 1973-1980 (Folder 8)
- Richard Nixon materials (Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1967-1974 (Folder 9)
- U.S. military housing study, 1964 (Folder 9)
- Veterans Administration health care service, 1969-1974 (Folder 10)
- Veterans Adminisration (Folder 11)
  - Drug program, 1972-1974 (Folder 11)
  - Benefits, 1972 (Folder 11)
  - Health care service, 1970-1974 (Folder 11)
  - Travel documents, 1971-1973 (Folder 11)
- Veterans Administration, 1968-1974 (Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1968-1974 (Folder 13)
- Veterans Administration, 1972-1973 (Folder 13)
  - Health care service, 1972 (Folder 13)
  - Reorganization, 1973 (Folder 13)
- White House staff, 1974 (Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1967-1973 (Folder 14)
- Veterans Administration, health care service, 1973 (Folder 14)
- Speeches, 1973 (Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1964-1974 (Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1953-1974 (Folder 16)
- U.S. military reserve units, 1955 (Folder 16)
- Recommendation letters (Folder 17)
- Campbell College (Folder 17)
- U.S. anti-aircraft units, 1953 (Folder 17)
- U.S. government spending, 1959-1964 (Folder 17)
- U.S. Senate Republican Policy Committee (Folder 17)
- Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Folder 18)
- Republican Convention, 1968 (Folder 18)
- U.S. Senate Republican Policy Committee, 1964-1971 (Folder 18)
- Veterans Administation, 1971-1973 (Folder 18)
- Atomic bomb (Folder 19)
- U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1944-1948 (Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1967 (Folder 19)
- Diary, 1953 March-August (Folder 19)
- U.S. Postal Rate Commission, 1974-1976 (Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1956-1961 (Folder 20)
- Correspondence, 1961-1973 (Folder 21)
- Biographical material (Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 1951-1974 (Folder 22)